Guide to the Andrzej Wolski Videorecordings for the documentary film Moi, Gombrowicz
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Andrzej Wolski videorecordings for the documentary film Moi, Gombrowicz
1988-1997
GEN MSS 948
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.96
(7 boxes)
Material consists of 57 Betacam videocassettes containing daily rushes created during the production of the film Moi, Gombrowicz, a French documentary directed by Andrzej Wolski and produced by France télévision (France 3 cinéma, Océaniques) in 1989, and copies of the film.The film commemorates the 20th anniversary of the death of the writer Witold Gombrowicz (1904-1969).
Wolski, Andrzej, 1952-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Rita Gombrowicz, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 1-7: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Andrzej Wolski
Andrzej Wolski (1952-), Polish film director, resides in France and specializes in biographies and documentaries. In addition to Moi, Gombrowicz, his films include Czapski (1985) and Jan Lebenstein - Dziennik samotnika (2000).
Scope and Contents
Material consists of 57 Betacam videocassettes containing daily rushes created during the production of the film Moi, Gombrowicz, a French documentary directed by Andrzej Wolski and produced by France télévision (France 3 cinéma, Océaniques) in 1989, and copies of the film. The film commemorates the twentieth anniversary of the death of the writer Witold Gombrowicz (1904-1969).
Arrangement
Arranged by tape number.
Motion picture producers and directors -- France; Authors, Polish -- 20th Century; Polish literature -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials; Videocassettes; Motion picture producers and directors -- France -- 20th Century; Gombrowicz, Witold, 1904-1969; Wolski, Andrzej, 1952-
- 1. Warszawa Kamienice, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0001; 1; 00:22:44 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338366)
- 2. Mme. Gawlikowska; Mr. Kępiński, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0002; 1; 00:24:58 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338374)
- 3. Kępiński, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0003; 1; 00:24:14 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338382)
- 4. Z. [Choudzińska?], [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0004; 1; 00:25:05 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338390)
- 5. [Choudzińska?]; Wsola; Bodzechów, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0005; 1; 00:24:44 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338408)
- 6. [M___jzyce]; Konwicki, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0006; 1; 00:24:26 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338416)
- 7. Konwicki, etc., [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0007; 1; 00:24:42 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338424)
- 8. Wystawa, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0008; 1; 00:24:44 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338432)
- 9. Wystawa, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0009; 1; 00:06:58 (Box 1, Item barcode 39002102338440)
- 10. Gombrowicz; Miłosz, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0010; 1; 00:24:36 (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338457)
- 11. Gombrowicz; Miłosz, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0011; 1; 00:24:23 (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338465)
- 12. Gombrowicz; Miłosz, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0012; 1; 00:24:21 (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338473)
- 13. Passeport/Zdjęncie przed wojny, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0013; 1; 00:23:22; There is no audio on this videotape. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338481)
- 14. Photo Argent., [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0014; 1; 00:23:47; There is no audio on the videotape. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338499)
- 15. Photo Berlin, Vence, Livres, 1989 March 7; GENMSS948_0015; 1; 00:23:45; There is no audio on the videotape. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338507)
- 16. Photo Vence; Polska; Ksiązki, 1989 March 8; GENMSS948_0016; 1; 00:23:09; There is no audio on the videotape. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338515)
  Scope and Contents
  There is no cassette numbered 17 present in the collection.
- 18. Théâtre, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0017; 1; 00:24:38 (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338523)
- 19. Théâtre, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0018; 1; 00:08:04; There is no audio on the videotape. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002102338531)
- 20. Son Seul; Bouquet cassette 1, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0019; 1; 00:24:43; There is audio over color bars. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338549)
- 21. Son Seul; Bouquet cassette 2, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0020; 1; 00:21:57; There is audio over color bars. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338556)
- 22. Son Seul; Bouquet cassette 3, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0021; 1; 00:15:18; There is audio over color bars. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338564)
- 23. Son Seul; Bouquet cassette 4, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0022; 1; 00:14:39; There is audio over color bars. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338572)
- 24., [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0023; 1; 00:25:19 (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338580)
  There are no cassettes numbered 25 or 26 present in the collection.
- 27. LIRE II, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0024; 1; 00:25:27 (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338598)
- 28. La seducción cassette 1, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0025; 1; 00:24:03 (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338606)
- 29. La seducción cassette 2, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0026; 1; 00:24:30 (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338614)
- 30. La seducción cassette 3, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0027; 1; 00:06:39 (Box 3, Item barcode 39002102338622)
  There is no cassette numbered 31 present in the collection.
- 32. Mariage Doc, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0028; 1; 00:09:08 (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338630)
- 33. Yvonne, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0029; 1; 00:03:57 (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338648)
- 34. Duprez cassette 1, 1989 January 10; GENMSS948_0030; 1; This tape was not digitized due to jamming problems. (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338655)
  There are two cassettes numbered 34 present in the collection.
- 34. Joris Ivens, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0031; 1; 00:13:49; The tape is in black and white. There is no audio. (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338663)
- 35. Duprez cassette 2, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0032; 1; 00:24:09; Color bars run through the whole tape. There is voice narration. (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338671)
- 36. Duprez cassette 3, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0033; 1; 00:16:09; Color bars run through the whole tape. There is voice narration. (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338689)
- 37. Bondy cassette 1, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0034; 1; 00:24:38 (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338697)
- 38. Bondy cassette 2, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0035; 1; 00:16:06 (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338705)
- 39. Jerzy Giedroyc, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0036; 1; 00:16:49 (Box 4, Item barcode 39002102338713)
- 40. Jerzy Giedroyc, DUB, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0037; 1; 00:16:49 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338804)
- 41. Josef Czapski, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0038; 1; 00:24:34 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338796)
- 42. Josef Czapski, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0039; 1; 00:13:57 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338788)
- 43. Rita Gombrowicz, 1988 December 8; GENMSS948_0040; 1; 00:22:52 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338770)
- 44. Rita Gombrowicz, 1988 December 8; GENMSS948_0041; 1; 00:21:53 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338762)
- 45. M. Nadaud, 1988 December 13; GENMSS948_0042; 1; 00:23:50 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338754)
- 46. M. Nadaud, 1988 December 13; GENMSS948_0043; 1; 00:11:04 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338747)
- 47. Philippe Sollers, 1988 December 14; GENMSS948_0044; 1; 00:24:24 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338739)
- 48. Philippe Sollers, 1988 December 14; GENMSS948_0045; 1; 00:21:44 (Box 5, Item barcode 39002102338721)
- 49. J. Lavelli, 1988 December 12; GENMSS948_0046; 1; 00:23:50 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338812)
- 50. J. Lavelli, 1988 December 12; GENMSS948_0047; 1; 00:23:38 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338820)
- 51. Christian Bourgois, 1988 December 13; GENMSS948_0048; 1; 00:24:46 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338838)
- 52. Christian Bourgois, 1988 December 13; GENMSS948_0049; 1; 00:09:29 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338846)
- 53. Karpinski, 1988 December 15; GENMSS948_0050; 1; 00:24:05 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338853)
- 54. Karpinski, 1988 December 15; GENMSS948_0051; 1; 00:24:38 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338861)
- 55. Karpinski, 1988 December 15; GENMSS948_0052; 1; 00:10:41 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338879)
  There are no cassettes numbered 56 or 57 present in the collection.
- 58. Texte son seul, [1988-1989]; GENMSS948_0053; 1; 00:13:08; The video is black, but there is audio. (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338887)
- "Gombrowicz pour Seweryn", [1997]; GENMSS948_0054; 1; 00:32:43 (Box 6, Item barcode 39002102338895)
- "Gombrowicz pour Seweryn Master", 1997 February 16; GENMSS948_0055; 1; 00:07:09 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102339067)
- FR3 Gombrowicz, undated; GENMSS948_0056; 1; 00:17:31 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102339075)
- "Moi, Gombrowicz," I and II, NTSC, undated; GENMSS948_0057; 1; 01:27:29 (Box 7, Item barcode 39002102338929)